This course is packed with content.
مدرس: هذه الدورة مليئة بالمحتوى.
We're almost done getting started
لقد انتهينا تقريبًا من البدء
and thereafter we'll dive right into TypeScript
وبعد ذلك سنتعمق في TypeScript
and into all it's exciting features
وفي جميع ميزاته المثيرة ونتعلمها
and learn them step by step.
خطوة بخطوة.
We'll start with the TypeScripts basics of course.
سنبدأ بالطبع بأساسيات TypeScripts.
The core types, how it generally works,
الأنواع الأساسية ، وكيف تعمل بشكل عام
some of the new features it adds,
، وبعض الميزات الجديدة التي تضيفها
and all you need to know to get a good
، وكل ما تحتاج إلى معرفته للحصول
understanding of TypeScript.
على فهم جيد لـ TypeScript.
Thereafter we'll already dive deeper
بعد ذلك ، سنتعمق بالفعل في مترجم
into the TypeScript compiler
TypeScript وتكوينه لأنه
and the configuration of it because it's super important
من المهم للغاية أن تفهم ما يمكنك تهيئته
for you to understand what you can configure there
هناك وما تفعله كل هذه الإعدادات المختلفة
and what all these different settings do
، لذا سنلقي نظرة فاحصة على ذلك في هذه الوحدة.
Thereafter we'll explore next generation JavaScript
بعد ذلك سوف نستكشف الجيل التالي من ميزات JavaScript
features supported in TypeScript.
المدعومة في TypeScript.
How they work and how you can use them in TypeScript.
كيف تعمل وكيف يمكنك استخدامها في TypeScript.
We'll continue with classes and interfaces,
سنستمر في استخدام الفئات والواجهات
a super important concept partly also in vanilla
، وهو مفهوم مهم جدًا جزئيًا أيضًا في Vanilla JavaScript
JavaScript in the case of classes,
في حالة الفئات ، ولكن مع الواجهات
but with interfaces we also got a brand new
، حصلنا أيضًا على ميزة TypeScript
TypeScript feature and you will understand
جديدة تمامًا وستفهم ما هي وماذا
what they are, what they do,
تفعل ولماذا نحن قد ترغب في استخدامها.
Thereafter it's time to dive deeper.
بعد ذلك حان الوقت للغوص بشكل أعمق.
We'll have a look at some advanced types
سنلقي نظرة على بعض الأنواع المتقدمة
and advanced TypeScript features in general
وميزات TypeScript المتقدمة بشكل عام ، وننتقل
taking it to the next level there
بها إلى المستوى التالي هناك
and building up on the basics
ونبني على الأساسيات التي
we already learned about up to this point.
تعلمناها بالفعل حتى هذه النقطة.
Also an advanced feature, which definitely
أيضًا ميزة متقدمة ، والتي تستحق
deserves it's own section, is the generics feature.
بالتأكيد قسم خاص بها ، هي ميزة الأدوية الجنسية.
You will learn what that is
سوف تتعلم ماهية ذلك
and why it's really, really helpful
ولماذا هو مفيد حقًا في هذه
in this module.
الوحدة.
Followed by decorators.
تلاه المصممون.
Decorators are a pretty cool feature
تُعد Decorators ميزة رائعة جدًا تمت
also added by TypeScript and we'll have a closer look
إضافتها أيضًا بواسطة TypeScript وسنلقي
at decorators and also build some really useful
نظرة فاحصة على الزخارف ونبني أيضًا بعض الزخارف
decorators in that module
المفيدة حقًا في تلك الوحدة وبعد
and thereafter we will have learned a lot
ذلك سنتعلم الكثير عن TypeScript.
Now, the course is organized such that I show
الآن ، تم تنظيم الدورة بحيث
all these individual features in relatively small
أعرض كل هذه الميزات الفردية في عروض توضيحية
simple demos.
بسيطة صغيرة نسبيًا.
Now to also give you a bigger picture
الآن لإعطائك صورة أكبر ومعرفة
and to see how you would apply all these features
كيفية تطبيق كل هذه الميزات في مشروع
in a real project, we'll build just that.
حقيقي ، سنقوم ببناء ذلك بالضبط.
We'll have a whole module where we build
سيكون لدينا وحدة نمطية كاملة
an entire project entirely with TypeScript
حيث نقوم ببناء مشروع كامل بالكامل باستخدام TypeScript
from scratch so that you see many of these features,
من البداية حتى ترى العديد من هذه الميزات ،
most of these features you learned about
ومعظم هذه الميزات التي تعلمتها
up to this point, in action
حتى هذه النقطة ، قيد التنفيذ
and you'll see how they work together
وسترى كيف تعمل معًا ولماذا
and why they simplify the process of building
يبسطون عملية بناء مثل هذا المشروع.
Once we're done building this project
بمجرد الانتهاء من بناء هذا المشروع
we'll identify a new problem
، سنحدد مشكلة جديدة وسنتعلم كيفية
and we'll learn how to solve it by working
حلها من خلال العمل مع مساحات الأسماء والوحدات
with namespaces and modules
النمطية التي ستساعدنا في جعل الكود
which will help us make our code
الخاص بنا أكثر قابلية للإدارة
more manageable and readable.
والقراءة.
Building up on that, we'll also explore
بناءً على ذلك ، سنستكشف أيضًا
Webpack with TypeScript.
Webpack مع TypeScript.
Webpack is a build tool we use in modern front end
Webpack هي أداة بناء نستخدمها في تطوير الويب للواجهة
web development and you can use it
الأمامية الحديثة ويمكنك استخدامها
combined with TypeScript to get a better project set up
جنبًا إلى جنب مع TypeScript للحصول على إعداد أفضل للمشروع
which simply makes certain things easier
مما يجعل بعض الأشياء أسهل ويسمح لك بالحصول
and allows you to get the best of bother worlds.
على أفضل العوالم المزعجة.
A great development experience
تجربة تطوير رائعة وأيضًا
and also code that works really well
رمز يعمل جيدًا للمستخدمين
for your end users.
النهائيين.
Once we're done with that we have a very solid
بمجرد الانتهاء من ذلك ، لدينا صورة
picture of TypeScript and how to work
قوية جدًا لـ TypeScript وكيفية العمل
with it in projects.
معها في المشاريع.
Now what you will need in a lot of real projects
الآن ما ستحتاجه في الكثير من المشاريع الحقيقية
are third party libraries
هو مكتبات تابعة لجهات خارجية
so we will take a closer look
، لذا سنلقي نظرة فاحصة على
at that because there are certain third party libraries
ذلك نظرًا لوجود مكتبات معينة تابعة لجهات خارجية
which really embraced TypeScript
احتضنت بالفعل TypeScript وقد
and have built in TypeScript support,
بنيت في دعم TypeScript ، ولكن هناك
but there also are many libraries
أيضًا العديد من المكتبات التي
which don't and we'll have a look at how we can work
لا سنلقي نظرة على كيفية العمل مع كلا
with both types of libraries in a great way
النوعين من المكتبات بطريقة رائعة في مشاريع TypeScript.
Well and then there are some specific
حسنًا ، هناك بعض السيناريوهات
scenarios which deserve their own modules.
المحددة التي تستحق وحداتها الخاصة.
We'll have a whole module about
سيكون لدينا وحدة كاملة حول
React with TypeScript, how you can build
React مع TypeScript ، وكيف يمكنك إنشاء
an entire React application with TypeScript only,
تطبيق React بالكامل باستخدام TypeScript
and also an entire module
فقط ، وأيضًا وحدة كاملة حول
about NodeJS and express end type script
NodeJS ونص كتابة النهاية السريعة بحيث يكون لديك أيضًا
so that you also have great examples
أمثلة رائعة لهذه الاستخدامات
for these very popular and specific use cases
الشائعة والمحددة حالات TypeScript حيث يمكنك
of TypeScript where you can suddenly
فجأة إنشاء تطبيقات React أو Node
create React or Node applications
بطريقة جديدة تمامًا باستخدام
in a brand new way with a brand new language.
لغة جديدة تمامًا.
So lots of exciting content in the course.
الكثير من المحتوى المثير في الدورة.
Let's not waste any time.
دعونا لا نضيع الوقت.
Let's see how you can get the most out
دعنا نرى كيف يمكنك تحقيق أقصى
of the course and thereafter let's dive in.
استفادة من الدورة وبعد ذلك دعنا نتعمق.